好漂亮啊
Very pretty
各位客官
Everybody!
耽搁大家一会儿 很快就点着了
I'm sorry to you. It'll be OK soon
不好意思 对不起呀
Sorry...sorry
老伯 你这样点灯是点不着的
Granny, you can't light it up in this way
你只有油 没有灯芯诶
You've just got the oil but you haven't got a lampwick
我知道
I know that
可是灯芯不见了 有什么办法呢
But I've lost the lampwick I can do nothing about it
买一根喏
Buy a new one
有道理
It's reasonable...
姑娘 请问你
Miss, excuse me
如果如来佛祖那盏神灯的灯芯不见了
if it is the lamp of Buddha
上哪去买
where to buy a new lampwick for it?
早知道你有问题 现身吧
Show your real image!
原来是二郎神和南天门的四大天王
The Four Kings from the Nantian Gate and Erland God
紫霞 你跟你姐姐青霞仙子
Zixia. Your sister Zixia and you
原来是佛祖日月明灯里面
is the lampwick
缠在一起的灯芯
inside the lamp of Buddha
你竟然擅自离开天庭
You left Heaven without permission
还到处跟人说
You told the public that
谁能拔出你手中的紫青宝剑
the one who can pull your Magic Sword out
就是你的如意郎君
is your best love
你是神仙怎么能动凡心
You're an immortal You can't love any ordinary man
假如邪魔外道把你的宝剑拔出来
If a devil pulls your sword out
我们仙界岂不是成为笑柄
we'll become the laughing-stocks
神仙也好 妖怪也好
No matter who he is an immortal or a devil
剑只有我跟我的意中人能拔得出
the sword can only be pulled out by me and my lover
就算他是妖怪
I will stand by him forever
我也会一生一世跟着他
如果不能跟我喜欢的人在一起的话
If I can't be with the one who I love
就算让我做玉皇大帝我也不会开心哪
I won't be happy even if I were Heaven Emperor
一派胡言
How dare you are
既然你执迷不悟
You're this stubborn
我今天就要替天行道
I'm gonna kill you
要你在人间仙界消失
You're gonna vanish
只羡鸳鸯不羡仙 消失就消失
That's fine I don't wanna be a lonely immortal
放肆
Look out!
不用说
No need to say anything
这件事谁说出去 我就杀了他
I'll kill whoever speaks it out
我说了不用再说了
I've said it's not permitted to speak it out
不是啊
I wanna tell you
你的哮天犬在那边骑着一条母狗
Your beloved dog is doing that with a bitch
连它都动了凡心
How dare it is!
今天晚上我就杀了它打牙祭
Ok, I'll kill it. Let's eat it
好啊
Ok...
我们早就这么想了
We've decided to do so for a long time
晶晶
Jing Jing
怎会这样呢 人呢
Jing Jing, where are they?
神仙
Immortals?
妖怪
Devils
谢谢
Thank you
盘丝洞不要乱闯
Please go into the Spider Web Cave
盘丝洞
Spider Web Cave?
你以为我看不懂啊 水帘洞嘛
Don't cheat me! It is the Waterfall Cave
盘丝洞 这个名字也蛮好听的
Spider Web Cave, what a nice name
就叫你盘丝洞吧
Just call it Spider Web Cave
好 我以后就住在这儿
I live at here
慢着
Hold it
我现在郑重宣布
Listen to me
这个山头所有东西都是属于我的
all things here belong to me!
包括你在内
Including you!
我
Me?
对
Yes
就像我的骡子一样 给你盖个章
just like a donkey let me make a mark on you
你现在是我的人了
You're my guy now
如果有人欺负你呢 就报我的名字
Don't scare of anyone Just tell them you know me
从今天起 我叫盘丝洞大仙
I'm called Spider Web Immortal now
盘丝大仙
Spider Web Immortal?
五百年前
500 years ago?
你没有变成孙悟空托世
You hasn't turned back into the Monkey King because
是因为你还没遇见给你三颗痣的人
you haven't met the guy who'll give you the 3 birthmarks
芝麻开门
Open the door
芝麻关门
Close the door
我不信
I can't believe it...
我不要当猴子
I don't wanna be the Monkey King
我要去救晶晶
I have to save Jing Jing
拜托你把宝盒还给我
Give me back the Box
芝麻开门
Open the door
没道理啊 我明明听到她说芝麻开门哪
I have heard that she said "open the door"
芝麻开门
Open the door
你赖皮
How dare you are?
怕了你了 想别的办法
Let's go there through another way
上山
Be careful
这边
That way
芝麻开门
Open the door
谁呀
Who?
怎么压得四分五裂了
Is it necessary?
哇 好棒啊
It's great!
有了这个月光宝盒
We needn't scare of Qingxia
以后就不怕被青霞姐姐追杀了
since we've got the box
出来呀 鬼鬼祟祟的 害羞呀你
Come out! Are you really this shy?
-这个月光宝盒呢 -我的
-this Box is... -It's me!
我说过了 这里所有东西都是我的
I've said that all things here are mine
你想干嘛
What do you want?
没有
Nothing...
我听说你要走
I've heard that you wanna go
能不能带我一起走啊
Can you bring me with you?
你也被人追杀啊
Are you also chased after by someone?
我赶着去救人哪
I'm going to save someone
救谁啊
Save whom?
救我娘子
Save my wife
就是白晶晶啊 你认识她的
It's Pak Jing Jing. You know her
不认识
I don't know her
我知道 不过你很快就会认识她了
I know that. But you'll know her soon
因为她将会做你的徒弟
Because she'll be your disciple
还有这个宝盒呢
And this Box...
我的
It's mine!
我知道
I know that
不过其实呢 是我给你
But in fact, I gave you this
然后你再 在那个时候交给我
Then, you gave me back at that time
那么才会有我回到这里来
So I come back and
然后又交还给你
give it back to you again now
你明白吗
Do you ynderstand?
-我明白了 你神经病 -对呀
-Yes, you're craZy -Yes
反正你一定要带我走就对了
And you have to bring me with you
我为什么要对你那么好
Why need I do so good to you?
因为你是我的主人哪
This is because you're my master
你走了我一个人留在这里有什么意思啊
It's meaningless if you leave me here
真的吗
Really?
坐
Sit down
地下
Ground
手
Give me your hand
乖啊 待会呢给你买件新衣服
I'll buy a new clothes
回去见你娘子
for you later
叫啊
Bark!
汪
Wow!
用心点
Loyder!
汪
Wow...
仙子
Immortal...
快点哪 月亮出来了
Be quick, the moon has come out
走啦
Go!
去哪儿
Where to go?
你不走啊
Are you leaving?
你不走把宝盒给我 我走
If you aren't, give me the Box I'm leaving
你说什么宝盒
What Box?
我是不会再等到明天晚上了
I won't wait until tomorrow
我告诉你
Listen to me
你快点嘛 还说
Be quick, shut up
等一下你那个贱人姐姐又出来害你了
Then your bitch sister will come here
贱人 到处跟人家说我会害她
Shit, how dare you tell the others that I do bad to her
什么
What?
我就是那个贱人的姐姐
I'm that bitch's sister
你说我坏话
Don't listen to her nonsense words
至尊宝
Joker
你昨晚怎么不叫醒我呀
Why didn't tell me to wake up last night?
怎么了
What?
你到哪儿去呀 站住
Where have you been? Stand still
坐下
Sit down
椅子
Chair
你怎么了
What about you?
怎么这样看我
Why are you looking at me in this way?
你看到什么啦
What did you see?
你看到她啦
Did you see her?
你真的看到我姐姐了
Did you see my sister?
她那么快就来啦
She's come
她跟你说了些什么
What did she tell you?
你不要相信她 她神经病诶
don't trust her, she's crazy!
可能她呢 前世跟我斗得太厉害了
Maybe she had a fierce fight with me in our past lives
所以后来佛祖呢
So Buddha
就把我们两个卷在一起变成一根灯芯
turned us into a lampwick
要我们呢 苦练修行
told us to practise more
化解这段恩怨
Solve our disputes
可惜事与愿违
But we couldn't do that
现在斗得比以前更厉害
We are still fighting with each other
不要说那么多了
don't say that anymore
我们快点走吧
Let's go
你以为我精神分裂啦
Do you think that I'm crazy?
我没有哇 那个真的是我姐姐
No. That's really my sister
你不相信是吧
Don't you believe me?
来呀 拿来呀
Come on, come on
我们把手绑在一起
Let's tie our hand up
今天晚上就知道了
You will know that tonight
我看今晚不会有月光了
I don't think the moon will come out tonight
是吗
Really?
贱人
Bitch
你跑不出我的五指山
You can't escape from me
贵姓啊
What's you name?
姓林
My surname is Lin?
原来你就是我大哥说的那个林青霞
You're Lin Qingxia My brother talks about you usually
你大哥
Your brother?
昨天被你打那个家伙 叫做至尊宝的
The guy who you beat up is called Joker
那你呢
How about you?
我是他的双胞胎弟弟叫至尊玉
I'm his twin brother Broker
至尊宝 玉尊玉 想骗我啊
Joker? Broker? You tell lies
你真是聪明伶俐
You're so smart
其实我大哥真名叫做秦汉
My brother is called Qin Han
我叫秦祥林
I'm called Qin Xiang Lin
你在这里干什么
What are you doing?
我很仰慕你
I admire you
你仰慕我
You admire me?
岂止仰慕 简直害怕失去你
Not only admire, I don't want to lose you
所以跟你绑在一起
So I tie myself with you
你接受我对你的爱吧
Please accept my love
我们一起远走高飞
Let's go together
爱我就要付出代价
You have to pay something for my love
别说了 反正你姐姐是恨你入骨
You hate your sister so much
我今天晚上骗她说杀了你
I've lied to her that I would kill you tonight
你以后就可以安稳了
Then you have nothing to worry
所以我要拿你身上一件信物给她看
So I have to take a thing as a sign
你有什么颈链呀
Do you have valuable thing such as...
手饰啊 金银珠宝啊 月光宝盒啊什么的
jewels or Pandora's Box...
好呀 不过那些没有用诶
ok, but they are useless
你今天晚上拿我的紫青宝剑给她看
Give her my Magic Sword tonight
她一定会相信的
She'll believe it
也好
Fine
居然是他
It's him
趁天没黑 带我到市集走走吧
Bring me to the market since it's not dark yet
怎么了
What?
干什么
What's up?
我的心跳得好厉害
My heart is pounding
那怎么办
What to do?
来
Follow me
现在大师兄变了人样
Now Big Brother has turned back into human face
还跟紫霞仙子在一起
and he's with Zixia Immortal
难道抓师父这件事
Did Zixia has a part in
紫霞仙子也有份
the capture of Master?
我们跟紧他不要打草惊蛇
We should keep it secret
论智慧跟武功呢
My martial arts skills and IQ
我一直比他高一点点
is better than him
可是现在多了一个紫霞仙子
But there is Zixia Immortal now
他恐怕比我高一点点了
She's better than me, I think
这边有我嘛
I'm here
就是因为多了你这个累赘
She's better than me because
他才会高我一点点
I've got a burden, it's you
这个猪头切一半给我 谢谢
Give me half of this pig head, thanks
猪头不卖 猪鞭要不要
I don't sell pig head Do you like pig penis?
干什么
What?
我的意中人在附近诶
My lover is nearby
你看到他了
Did you see him?
没有
No
因为我的紫青宝剑发出嘟嘟的讯号
because my Magic Sword is beeping
哪来的嘟嘟声啊
Where does the beeping sound come from?
嘟 嘟 嘟 对不对
Do...do...do...right?
你嘟的 宝剑没嘟啊
you made this, not the sword
我知道 你听不见我才嘟给你听的嘛
I know you didn't hear that So I made it for you
完了 我好害怕
I'm scared!
我不骗你 我真的好害怕
I'm really scared!
你怕什么
What?
这段姻缘是上天安排的 你说我怕不怕
It's fate. So don't be afraid
又来了
Come again?
是啊 我的心在跳
My heart is pounding
我的宝剑在嘟
My heart is beeping
怎么办
What?
怎么跟他说 怎么跟他说啊
How should I tell him?
你就告诉他
Just tell him
这是上天安排了这么一段姻缘
it is fate
他不喜欢我怎么办
If he doesn't like me, what to do?
他有老婆怎么办
If he has wife, what should I do?
你管他那么多 上天安排的最大嘛
It's fate. It's God's order He has to accept this
真的
Really?
上天安排的 还不够你臭屁的啊
It's fate! He has to accept this
对啊 对
Yes! Yes...
他来了
He's come
不会是我吧
It's me?
哎 就是你 你怎么知道 就是你
It's you. How do you know? It's you
你知不知道我刚才都不知道
I didn't know
该怎么跟你说才好
how to tell you
你真是聪明
You're so smart
可是我有老婆了
But I have a wife
我知道 可是我也没办法啊
I know, but I can do nothing about it
这段姻缘是上天安排的 最大嘛
This is fate. You have to accept this
唉 你现在呢 只有甩掉你那个老婆
You just need to leave your wife
然后跟我一起走
And then follow me
也好啊
That's great!
好啊
Fine?
是很好啊
That's fine
那我们大家立刻开始这段感情吧
Let's start our affair
好 就立刻开始
Ok, let's start
你先亲我一下
Kiss me first
哟嗬 自动送上门来
Fine, come to me
来啊
Come!
把宝盒给我吧
Give me!
你骗我
You deceive me
你根本不想亲我
You don't wanna kiss me
你刚刚说的话全都是骗我的
You deceived me! You lied to me!
我是认真的 你先把宝盒拿出来
I'm serious. Give me the Box first
要不要我把心托出来给你看看哪
Should I show you my heart?
不用 我自己来
No, I do this
哇 你的心怎么像椰子一样
Wow! Your heart looks like a coconut
小姐 不可否认我长得很丑
Miss, I'm ugly
可是我很温柔 而且永远不会说谎
But I'm a gentleman
那你老实告诉我
Tell me honestly
他跟他娘子是不是很恩爱呀
does she love his wife?
谁敢惹我就杀谁
I'll kill the one who're gonna block my way
菩提大哥 你看看
Granpa Buddha, look
看看
Look!
真的不动啊
He doesn't move
我懂了
I know that
搜搜看
Let's go
老兄 这什么意思啊
Brother, what is this mean?
我看你身材好 所以摸摸看啦
I know you've got good figure so I touch you
是这样的啊 那就请继续摸吧
Yes, please go on
没事了 继续摸
That's fine. Touch me again
谁的手
Whose hand is it?
你说什么
What are you talking about?
拿开
Take away
妖怪呀
Devil
闹够了没
Have you finished?
你别生气 我是跟你闹着玩的
Don't get angry, I just do that for fun
宝盒在我姐姐那儿
Take care of sister
她一定会给你的
She will give you back
我怎么敢生你的气呢 大姐
Sister, I won't angry at you
把你当观世音供着还来不及呢
We should regard you as Goddess and worship you
天黑了 我要去找姐姐了
It's dark. I will go to find sister
祝你好运
Good luck
有好运才怪
It's really lucky
青霞
Qingxia
你在那里呀
Where are you?
出来呀
Come out
我已经杀了你妹妹啦
I've killed your sister
孙悟空
Monkey King
你这个畜生
You bastard
你为了跟牛魔王的妹妹成亲
You wanted to marry the King Bull's sister
居然把你师父唐三藏作贺礼
But you regarded the Longevity Monk as a wedding gift
还约了妖魔鬼怪一起吃唐僧肉
And you invited all devils to eat his flesh
你认不认错
Do you admit your guilt?
三八婆
Bitch!
你追了我三天三夜
She's chased me for 3 whole days
因为你是女人 我才不杀你
I didn't beat you up because you're a woman
不要以为我是怕了你
Don't think I'm scared of you
悟空
Monkey King
你怎么可以这样跟观音姐姐讲话呢
Don't say that to Goddess
闭嘴
Shut up!
你又吓我
You scare me again!
孙悟空 唐三藏
Monkey King, Longevity Monk?
你知不知道你已经犯了弥天大罪了
Do you know you've committed offences
你还抢了紫霞仙子的月光宝盒
You've grabbed Zixia Immortal's Pandora's Box
分明就是想避开我
You don't want to see me
既然避不了
Now, I can't escape
我老孙就跟你决一死战啦
I'm gonna fight against you!
干什么呀
What's up?
悟空 你也真调皮啊
Monkey King, you're so naughty
我叫你不要乱扔东西啊
I've told you don't throw things
乱扔东西是不对的
It's wrong to throw things
我话没说完 你怎么把棍子也给扔掉了
I haven't finished yet You've thrown away the stick
月光宝盒是宝物
The Box is a treasure
乱扔会染污环境
You'll pollute the environment!
砸到小朋友怎么办
What to do if kids are hurt?
就算砸不到小朋友
It's still bad
砸着花花草草也不好嘛
if you hurt plants
你干什么
What are you doing?
放手
Let go!
你想要呀
What do you want?
你想要说清楚了就行了嘛
Tell me if you like it
你想要的话我会给你的
I will give you that if you like it
你想要我当然不会不给你啦
Of course, I will give you if you like it
不可能你说要我不给你
I won't give you if you don't like it
你说不要我却偏要给你
I'm pretty sure that I won't give you if you don't like it
大家讲道理嘛
We're reasonable
现在我数三下
I'll count to 3
你要说清楚你要不要
Tell me if you want it!
孙悟空
Monkey King
大家看到了
You know him now
这家伙没事就长篇大论 婆婆妈妈
This guy is very annoying
叽叽歪歪
Ver disturbing
就活像整天有一只苍蝇
Just like a fly
对不起 不是一只
Sorry, not a fly
是一堆苍蝇围着你
but a swarm of flies
飞到你的耳朵里面
Fly into your ears
救命呀
Help...
Help!
所以我就抓住这只苍蝇挤破它肚子
So I tear the fly's belly open
把它肠子扯出来
Tear out its intestines
再用它肠子勒住它脖子 用力一拉
Put them around its neck, then pull them
整条舌头都伸出来了 我再手起刀落
Then its tongue comes out and I use my blade to cut!
整个世界清静了
The world's silent then
现在大家知道
We all know this now
我为什么要杀它
why I kill it
真的吗
Really?
诸多借口
So many excuses
你根本不想去取西经
You don't want to get scriptures
不管怎么解释也不能原谅你
I won't forgive you
欺师灭祖的行为
because you're so cruel to your master
姐姐
Sister
这是你的不对了
you're wrong
悟空他要吃我
The Monkey King wanted to eat me
只不过是一个构思
It's just a thought
还没有成为事实
Not a fact
你又没有证据
You haven't got any evidence
它又何罪之有呢
He's not guilty!
不如等它吃了我之后
Just wait, when he's eaten me up
你有凭有据 再定它的罪也不迟
you can prove him guilty
唐三藏 你啰嗦我早就听说过了
Longevity Monk, I know you're annoying
不过没想到你居然这么啰嗦
But I don't know you're this annoying
我给你的金刚圈要你用来制服这猴子
I gave you the Gold Ring to control this monkey
你居然不用
But you don't use the ring
那个金刚圈尺寸太差
The siZe of that ring doesn't suit him
前重后轻 左宽右窄
He can't wear it
他戴上之后很不舒服
It makes him very uneasy
整晚失眠 会连累我嘛
He can't sleep at night It disturbed me, too
它虽然是个猴子
Although it is just a monkey
可是你也不能这样对它呀
you cannot do that do it
官府知道会说我虐待动物的
I'll be indicted animal abused if the government knows it
说起那个金刚圈
That Gold Ring...
去年我在陈家村认识了一位铁匠
I met iron-smith last year at the Chan's village
他手工精美 价钱又公道
His skill is wonderful and the price is low
童叟无欺
Really fair price
干脆我介绍你
I think
再订做一个吧
you should buy a new one from him
闭嘴
Shut up!
罪过
It's a sin...
现在你能够体会我的痛苦了吧
Now, I think you know my pain!
回答我
Answer me!
搞定了
It's Ok!
我叫你不要乱扔东西嘛
I've told you not to throw things
你看看 真是的
Look!
妖猴受死吧
Monkey devil, go to hell
凭你也想收服我
You can't defeat me!
你以为你是如来佛祖啊
You're not Buddha
不要打了
No more fighting...
观音姐姐
Goddess
请你放了悟空 不要伤害它
Please let the Monkey King go don't hurt him
你们不要打了
No more fighting
今天我要替天行道
I'm gonna kill him!
观音姐姐 手下留情啊
Goddess, stop!
试问人谁无过
It's normal to make mistakes
它总算是我的徒弟
He's my disciple
徒弟有错 做师父的也有责任
I have to take the responsibility
求观音姐姐放它一条生路吧
Goddess, please let him go
我不消灭它
If I won't kill him
无法向玉皇大帝交代
I can't report to Heaven Emperor
我不会使你为难的
I know that
请观音姐姐跟玉皇大帝说一声
Please tell Heaven Emperor that
贫僧愿意一命赔一命
I'm gonna sacrifice my life to him
啊
What?
正所谓我不入地狱 谁入地狱
It is a master's responsibility
求姐姐你体谅
Goddess, please listen to me
我这样做 无非是想感化劣徒
I just wanna teach him...
以配合我佛慈悲的大无畏精神啊
in order to show my spirit
善哉
That's great...
悟空 希望你有一天能够领悟到
Monkey King, I hope you'll learn
你师父这种舍身取义的精神
your master's spirit!
南无阿弥陀佛
Namonitabhaya
难道又做梦了
Dreaming again?
这次麻烦大了
It's big trouble
没有一次做的梦是好梦
I always have nightmares
青霞呢
Where is Qingxia?
没来过啊
Not here
青霞
Qingxia...
各位兄台 大家好啊
Everybody, how are you?
天气好冷啊
It's cold!
有没有多穿件衣服啊
Have you worn more clothes
小弟一时迷失了方向
I've lost my way
想借个地方睡一个晚上
I wanna find a place to stay at night
马屁精 到那边睡去
Go there to sleep
真是出门遇贵人
Thank you very much
祝大家万寿无疆啊 谢谢啦
Wish you all long live
明明看见大师兄上来的呀
I saw him come here
怎么人不见了
Where is he now?
都是你害的 尿什么尿嘛
Why did you go to pee? You have to take the blame
忍忍会憋死呀
It won't hurt you
尿尿也犯法呀
Is it illegal?
黑山老妖
Old Black Mountain Devil?
悟空
Monkey King
你又扮人样啦
You turn into human face again
还认得为师吗
Do you still recognise me?
又是你这只苍蝇
You are the fly
悟空
Monkey King...
不可能 一定是在作梦
Impossible, I must be dreaming
悟空要做梦还早着呢 不过
It is still early to make dreams, but...
我在时空穿梭的时候
I dream of you
经常在梦里见到你
when I was travel through time and space
你是不是很想念为师
Do you miss me?
对了 那个月光宝盒是不是在你哪里
The Box is at your side?
是在我这儿 你还想要
Yes, it is. Do you want it?
谁呀
Who?
什么事
What's up?
有官兵
Soldier
Soldier?
他也想在这儿借住一个晚上 是我老爸
My dad also wanna stay here
没问题吧
No problem
你老爸
It's your dad!
是啊 老爸 出来跟诸位大哥打招呼
Yes, dad, come out to say hello to all bros
他哪儿来的
Where does he come from?
印度来的
From India
印度 怎么没听过
India? Where is it?
我们明天还要赶路 你睡那边吧
I need to carry on tomorrow. Sleep there
多谢
Thanks
真吵死人了
It's really noisy
烦不烦呀
Annoying
睡里面
Sleep inside
真要命 时差不对
It is the problem of time difference
刚刚从印度那边才睡醒 现在又要我睡
I have just slept in India Now you tell me to sleep again
叫要你睡 你就睡啦
You go to sleep
月光宝盒在哪里
Where is the Pandora's Box?
悟空 你斯文一点行不行啊
Monkey King, can you behave yourself?
为什么老那么猴急呢 你看
Look, just keep calm
他在干什么
What is he doing?
他在吸阳气啊
He's breathing in life
装睡吧
Pretend to sleep
希望他吸饱了别人就不吸我们了
I hope that he won't breath in ours
快睡啊
Go to sleep!
你不认得我了
Do you know me?
刚刚那个印度阿三嘛
That Indian...
哦 你喜欢 拿去吧
You like it, take it
我徒弟叫我了 byebye
My disciple is calling me, bye bye
我叫你不要玩火了嘛
Don't play with fire again
阿弥陀佛 goodbye
bye
我又不认识你们 拜托不要跟着我
Please don't follow us. I don't know you
师父能够见到你真好了
It's great to see you
盒子呢 盒子呢
Where is the Box? The Box?
又是牛魔王
The King Bull?
贤弟 你把唐僧抓来给我啦
Bro. catch the Longevity Monk and give him to me
小姐 毛巾
Miss, handkerchief
结婚嘛 你哭什么哭
It's wedding day, why are you weeping?
我不是哭 我看到你流口水呀
I'm not weeping. My mouth is watering
今天是双喜临门
It's a very happy day
为什么
What?
今天除了舍妹出阁之日
It's not only the wedding day of my sister
也是我雄牛纳妾之时
but also the day of my marriage with my concubine
你说纳妾
Concubine?
那大嫂没有意见
What does sister-in-law say about this?
那黄脸婆
That bitch
现在在十万九千里外的火焰山里
She's now at the Flame Mountain
就算她知道也奈何不了我
She can do nothing about this even if she knows it
牛大哥你能说说你怎么认识
Bull, how did you know
这位新夫人的
this new wife?
我前天路过洛阳沙漠
I passed the desert yesterday
看到一个貌美如花的女子
I saw a pretty girl
趴在地上奄奄一息
She's dying
大师兄 现在怎么办
Master, what to do now?
好了 没问题啦
Fine! No problem...
真的没问题啦
Really? We succeed now!
紫霞 你的名字太好听了
Zixia, what a nice name you've got
来 我来介绍我妹妹和妹夫给你认识
Let me introduce my sister and my brother-in-law to you
香香 贤弟
Xiang Xiang, Bro
来 过来
Come here, follow me
这个呢 是我妹夫
This my brother-in-law
这是我妹妹香香
This is my sister Xiang Xiang
紫霞姑娘
Zixia!
你能留在这里成亲吗
How can you get marry here?
可以吧
I can!
那你家里的老婆怎么办
How about your wife?
老婆 你们两个认识吗
My wife? Do you know her?
你有老婆
You've got a wife?
已经离婚了
We're divorced
怎么我从来就没有听你说过呢
I haven't heard you say that before
哎 妹妹
Sister...
男人有三妻四妾很平常嘛
It's normal that a man has many wives
别那么紧张
Take it easy
贤弟 你说对不对
Bro, do you think so?
对
Yes...
紫霞 实不相瞒
Zixia, be honest
经过这两天朝夕相处
I think I've fallen for you
我发觉我已经深深的爱上了你
after these two days
为了表示对你的诚意
I wanna show my sincerity
我当着这么多兄弟面前向你求婚
Thus I'm gonna request you to marry me in front of my bros
这个月光宝盒
This Pandora's Box
是我送给你的订情信物
is my gift to you
希望你能嫁给我
I hope you'll marry me
我反对这门亲事
I object this marriage!
你说什么
Why?
让我来 说什么
Let me speak...
人家郎才女貌 天生一对
What a good couple they are!
轮到你这妖怪来反对
You're a devil you're not qualified to object
紫霞仙子择偶是有一个规矩的
You have to pass Zixia's test first
如果大哥你能做得到的话
If you can pass it
我们就心服口服
I won't object it anymore
有什么规矩呀
What test?
她曾经发誓
She has sworn that
如果谁能把紫青宝剑拔出鞘的话
she would marry the guy
就是她的如意郎君哪
who could pull out
紫青宝剑
her Magic Sword
让我来
Listen to me
没有这种事
It's untrue
这个只不过是我跟大家开的一个玩笑
It's just a joke
开玩笑
What joke?
这把剑谁拔得出 谁拔不出
It's not important
根本没有关系
who can pull out the sword
你们这些混蛋在我地盘瞎搞和
Stop nagging in my place!
谁敢阻我谁就死
I'm gonna kill the ones who block my way
谁敢阻止我 我就杀了谁
大王 铁扇公主来了
King, Iron Fan Princess has come
哎呀 你怎么躲在这里呀
Why are you here?
当时那把剑离我的喉咙
At this time, the sword is close to me
只有零点零一公分
0.01cm I think
但是四分之一柱香之后
But after 0.01 seconds
那把剑的女主人将会彻底的爱上我
the owner of the sword will fall for me
因为我决定说一个谎话
This is because I've decided to tell lies
虽然本人生平说了无数的谎话
Although I have told many lies before
但是这一个 我认为是最完美的
this is the best, I think
你再往前半步 我就把你给杀了
You're gonna kill me if you step forward again
你应该这么做
You should do that
我也应该死
I deserve to die
曾经有一份真诚的爱情放在我面前
I have had my best love before
我没有珍惜
but I didn't treasure her
等我失去的时候
When I lose her
我才后悔莫及
I fell regretful
人世间最痛苦的事莫过于此
It is the most painful matter in this world
你的剑在我的咽喉上割下去吧
Just cut my throat!
不用再犹豫了
No hesitation
如果上天能够给我一个
If God can give me
再来一次的机会
another chance
我会对那个女孩子说三个字
I will say 3 words to her
我爱你
I love you
如果非要在这份爱上加一个期限
If you have to give a time limit to this love
我希望是 一万年
I hope it is 10 thousand year
那么你怎么向你娘子交代
Byt how will you tell your wife?
一定要交代
I have to tell her
所以我一定要拿回那个月光宝盒
So I must get the Box back
带你一起回去 跟她们说清楚
Tell her clearly and go back with you
我不管别人怎么说我
I won't listen to the others opinions
我也不怕后世会有千千万万的人
I won't listen to the others
对我唾骂
objections
我一个人承担下来
I will take all those on my own
你不会骗我吧
Don't lie to me!
但是我痛恨我自己没有本事
But I hate myself
拿回那个月光宝盒
because I can't get back the Box
我
I
我帮你
I'll help you
不用 太危险了
No! it's dangerous
你不想
You don't want
想
I want
我怎么会金屋藏娇呢
I won't hide a woman
谣言啊 夫人
It's just rumour
鬼才相信你
I won't trust you anymore...
你们在这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
她是谁啊
Who's he?
我问你啊 她是谁
I'm asking you, who's he?
她
He
贤弟 她是谁 你说呀
Bro, who's he? Tell me
他 是我的发妻
He's my wife
哇 贤弟 你太过份了
Bro, it's too much of you
好哥们
Bros
你居然还把妹妹嫁给他
You marry your sister to him!
所以他老婆看不过去 用剑指他呀
So his wife pointed a sword at him
你跟我过来 我有话要问你
You follow me I have something to ask you
原来你有老婆啊
You've got a wife
感情破裂了
I've lost my feeling to her
你跟我说清楚 到底发生什么事啦
Tell me what's going on
我说过啦 大嫂
I've told you...Sister-in-law
你叫我大嫂
Sister-in-law?
对不起 应该是牛夫人
Sorry, Madam Bull
以前陪我看月亮的时候
When you watched the moon with me in the past
叫人家小甜甜
you called me Sweetie
现在新人胜旧人啦 叫人家牛夫人
Now you yet your new lover! Call me Madam Bull?
小甜甜
Sweetie?
你以为我这么辛苦来这里
Do you think that I come here for
真的是为了这条臭牛吗
that ugly Bull?
是为了你这个没良心的臭猴子啊
I come here for you, heartless monkey
贤弟 真是难为你了
Bro, thank you
It's none of business
不关我的事
我不管
Sorry
今晚二更时分 你要在这儿等我
wait for me here at midnight
我有话要跟你说
I have something to tell you
如果我是你呀
If I were you
我老公要讨小老婆 我就死了算了
I'll die when my husband decides to get a concubine
真的
Really?
没错 不过要先把你阉了
Yes! But I'll castrate you first
跟我走
Follow me
紫霞 其实我
Zixia, I...
我相信你
I trust you
今天我去拿月光宝盒
I'll get the Box today
二更在这里见
Wait for me here at midnight
师兄
Bro...
我搞定我的兄弟先
Let me go to see my bros first
晚上见
See you tonight
死猴子 都二更了还不出现
Damn monkey, it's midnight now Where is he?
大师兄
Big Brother!
对不对呀
I've told you that
我早跟你说过啦 大师兄不会敷衍我们
Big Brother won't do so to us
一定会来救师父的
He'll come to save Master
这么晚出来难道是尿尿的吗
Gout at night, wanna pee?
不要夸
No need to praise me
我高你一点点 没什么大不了啦
I'm just better than you a little bit
别那么多废话 快去救师父吧 走
Stop nagging, go to save Master
受不了啦
I can't take this anymore
我肯定师父就在这里面了
I'm sure that Master is inside
对
Right...
除了他之外 没有别人会让人这么受不了
He's very annoying I can't take this anymore
你们进去先
You go in, I stay back...
走吧你 你在中间
Go! You at the middle
这边 师父在这里 进去吧
This way...Master is here, go in
师父
Master
Master, master
我们来带你走的
We come to bring you out
我不会走的
I won't go
嗯 为什么 什么 你不走
Really? Why? No
我们师徒四人这次取西经
There're full of obstacles in the way of
可以说是困难重重
getting scriptures
原因是我们不同心协力
This is because we're not united enough
所以被妖魔得逞
so the devils can do bad to us
既然是这样
Ok, now it is the case
我在这监狱里跟在外面有什么分别呢
Staying in this prison or not is just the same
外面对我来说
The outside world
只不过是个大一点的监狱
is just a larger prison to me
你们先出去 我有话跟大师兄说
You go out first I have something to talk to Big Brother
师父
Master
八戒 你又不听话啦
Piggy, you're naughty again
不是啊 师父
No, Master
我在外面帮你把风啊
I go out and protect you
沙僧 跟我来
Sandy, follow me. Yes
你走开
You stand aside
吹个球 吹个大气球
Blow up and blow up the ball
你东西掉了
You've dropped your thing
师弟呀 收拾一下
Bro, keep it
为什么要我收啊
Why should I keep it?
因为我本领比你高一点嘛
Because I'm stronger than you
高你个头
Stronger than your shit!
你进来坐吧
Come in and have a sit
坦白说 我不是你的徒弟
Honestly, I'm not your bro
我更不想是你的徒弟
I don't want to be your disciple
大师 你慈悲为怀
Master, be kind to me
你就放了我一马吧 好吧
Please let go of me, alright?
你知不知道什么是当当
Do you know what "Dong, Dong..."is?
什么当当当啊
What "Dong, Dong, Dong"?
♪ Only you 能伴我取西经 ♪
♪ Only you... can take me to get scriptures in the west ♪
♪ Only you 能杀妖和除魔 ♪
♪ Only you... can kill the devils ♪
♪ Only you 能保护我 ♪
♪ Only you... can protect me ♪
♪ 叫螃蟹和蚌精无法吃我 ♪
♪ No need to eat by the monster ♪
♪ 你本领最大 就是Only you ♪
♪ Only you are that strong ♪
♪ Only you 别怪师父嘀咕 ♪
♪ Only you... don't blame the master so talkative ♪
♪ 戴上紧箍儿 ♪
♪ Wear the ring back ♪
♪ 别怕死 别颤抖 ♪
♪ Don't scare the death ♪
♪ 背黑锅我来 送死你去 ♪
♪ Don't scare the shit ♪
♪ 拼全力为众生 牺牲也值得 ♪
♪ Do your best, if you scare I'll be with you... ♪
♪ 南无阿弥陀佛 ♪
♪ Namonitabhaya ♪
我真的不行啊 我跟你说
I can't take this anymore!
喔你妈个头啊 你有完没完哪
Oh your shit! Stop it!
我已经说了不行了
I've said I can't take this anymore
你还要喔
Byt you still sing
完全不理人家受得了受不了你
You disregard my feelings
你再喔 我一刀捅死你
I'll kill you if you sing again
悟空 你尽管捅死我吧
Monkey King, you kill you again
生又何哀 死又何苦
Life and death are minor
等你明白了舍身取义
You'll sing this song with me
你自然会回来跟我唱这首歌的
when you know making sacrifices is so meaningful
南无阿弥陀佛
Namonitabhaya...
紫霞
Zixia
师兄 你干嘛带个女人走啊
Bro, why are you taking a woman with you?
师父已经走了
Master has gone
叫你们在三百里外大树林等他
He said we had to wait for him at the forest 300 miles away
你们快去 拜托
Go there quickly, please
等等
Hold it!
干什么
What?
前面有埋伏
Ambush at the front
一眼就看出来啦 还听什么听嘛
I can see it, no need to listen
真是白痴
Stupid
来 抱着
Hold you
香香
Xiang Xiang!
你怎么在这里呀
Why are you here?
怎么那么多血呀 你的手
Wow! Why is there so much blood on your hand?
这些血
This is the blood
是你抱着的女人的
of the woman you're holding
是她的
Her blood?
没错
Yes! It's hers
今天晚上
I stabbed her
我趁她睡着的时候捅了她几刀
when she's sleeping
这个女人一天不死
If this woman is still alive
你就一天不会回到我身边的
you won't come back to me
这种事情怎么能勉强呢
You have to let it be
天意怎样就是怎样嘛
It is fate
废话
Bullshit!
上天要你喜欢猪八戒
If it is fate that you love Piggy
你会不会喜欢他
will you love him?
上天要真的这么安排
If this is God's order
那我也没有办法
I have to accept it
好
Great!
不用上天安排
You don't have to wait for God's order
你想干什么
Wow! What are you going to do?
快走 走啊
Go, go...
移形换影大法
Changing Image Magic!
我要把你跟石头调换
I will turn you into a rock
放开我
Let go of me!
抓你的胸部啊
Grab your breasts!
紫霞
Zixia...!
你醒醒啊
Wake up
大师兄 你干嘛搂着我啊
Big Bro, why are you embracing me?
猪八戒
Piggy?
是呀
Yes!
那紫霞呢
Where is Zixia?
秦祥林
Qin Xianglin...
青霞
Qingxia?
这玩笑开大了吧
Wow! Please don't play joke!
完了 连我也中招了
I'm also hurt!
我两块胸肌都掉到肚脐上了
My chest muscles nearly touch my stomach
你不会嫌弃我吧
Do you hate me?
当然不会
No!
你明明就是嫌弃我
You hate me!
好 从此一刀两断
Fine! End now!
你给一点时间
Stop! Give me some time
我吐哇吐哇的就会习惯了
I just vomit. I'll vomit all things out soon
好 我相信你
Fine! I trust you
我给你一点时间
Give you some time
等你吐惯了再说
Try to get used to it now
我习惯了
I'm used to it already
别再说了
Fine, I'm OK
连我都想吐啦
I wanna vomit!
都怪你 长得跟猪一样
You're so disgusting!
要不然的话他会吐成这样子吗
If you're not, he won't vomit
他为我着想
Please be good to me
我决定嫁给他
I will marry him
我要给他一个温暖的家庭
I'll give him a warm family
为他生很多很多小孩子
Give birth to many kids
祥林
Xianglin
我要杀了你
I will kill you!
杀了你
Kill you
师弟 你也中招了
Bro, you're also hurt?
你快给我换过来
Turn me back!
别吵
Shut up!
告诉你 不为难你呀
Listen to me!
你赶快发功 把我们换回来
Change me back!
你以为我不想吗
I also want to do so!
发一次功要等七天之后
I've used my power once
才能发第二次的嘛
I need 7 days to recover
七天以后啊 我
7 days! I...
祥林 你面对现实吧
Xianglin, face the reality!
你不快发功 我要你好看
Use your energy!
快发功 少装蒜啊
Use your energy! Stop playing!
快点
Be quick!
谁在我里面
Who is inside you?
谁在你里面 我也不知道我自己在哪儿
I don't know where I am
两个声音
Two voices?
你是谁呀
Who are you?
我是猪八戒啊 你呢
I'm Piggy. Who are you?
我是紫霞
I'm Zixia
祥林
Xianglin
至尊宝
Joker
师兄
Bro
紫霞
Zixia
紫霞 你还在这里呀
Ziaxia, you're still here
你这个贱人
You bitch!
终于被我看到你了
I find you at last
你怎么啦
What are you doing?
没见多久怎么变成这个样子啊
Long time no see, and you become this
月光宝盒呢
Where's the Pandora's Box?
忘了拿啦
I didn't take it
骗你的
Kidding
拿来
Give me
等一等
Wait
你拿月光宝盒干什么
What will you do to the Box?
跟我远走高飞呀
Go with me!
你不要缠着他 肥婆
Fat woman! Don't hang around with me
祥林会跟你远走高 牛魔王
Xianglin will go away with you... The King Bull
少在那做白日梦
Don't dream
你不信啊 你问问他
you ask him if you don't believe it
你说喜欢我
You said you love me
就是为了拿这个跟她远走高飞
because you wanna take this and
是不是
go away with her?
等等
Wait...
完全没这回事
It's not true
不信你扔掉这块烂东西吧
Don't want you to throw it away
好
Great!
做人干嘛那么认真 冲动呢
You should not do that
你看你那副贱相
Look at you
你还说不是呢
Don't deny it!
我就扔掉它
I'll throw that away!
哥哥
Bro...
好有男子气慨
What a man!
闭嘴
Shut up!
我很喜欢
I love that!
看你们能跑到哪儿去
You can't leave anymore
牛兄 你怎么伤成这样
Bull, you're seriously hurt
你以为那黄脸婆比我伤得轻吗
Do you think that bitch hurt lesser?
你看看
Have a look!
你骗得我好惨哪
You've deceived me so long
其实我根本就不是
In fact, I'm not
祥林 她是谁呀
Xianglin, who's that woman?
我相信你才怪
I won't listen to you!
混蛋 我们现在正式离婚
Bastard! I'll leave you
以后谁也别管谁
You affairs are none of my business
好 你要你的 我要我的
You get yours! And I get mine!
快点救紫霞 肉身你也有份的
Help Zixia, you have a part in the body
打得血肉模糊的 拿回来也没用啦
Beat it up, make it hurt! Then you can do nothing about it even if you
对
Yes!
想跑
Wanna go?
今天不说清楚别想走
Explain it clearly or you can't leave!
不准打他
Don't hit him!
死肥婆
Bitch
我跟他的事用不着你帮忙
Bitch, stand aside it's none of your business
省省吧
Stop it!
我是怕他打坏我的肉身
I'm afraid that she'll hyrt my body
鬼才有空帮你
I won't help you
打就打 那么多废话干嘛
Shut up!
当心我帮他一起打你呀
I'll help her and beat you up
你试试看
Have a try!
我是女人诶 玩真的 我跟你拼了
I'm a woman. Please don't hit her strongly I'll kill you
我就不帮你们 看你们打多久
I won't give help I just wanna see your fight!
快走
Go!
不行
No
我一定要帮你把月光宝盒拿回来
I'll take the Box for you
好让你跟你娘子有个交待
And you can explain to your wife
你这个人真讲义气 没话说
Wow, you're great! Perfect!
真的
Really?
你都这么做了 我还有什么话说
You're as perfect as possible
等等
Wait!
你
You!
黄脸婆 别打我马子
Bitch, don't hit my girl
我喜欢
I like to do it
你的小白脸跑了
Your man has gone
跑都跑得那么帅
How cool he is!
我真幸福
I'm a lucky woman!
没办法 假装跳一下吧
Ok, I can play jumping down from the cliff
摆近一点比较像
Go nearer
孙悟空
Monkey King
别跳下去
Don't jump!
鬼才想跳哪
I don't want to do so
你宁愿跳悬崖也不肯见我
You prefer jumping down to seeing me
算了 我还是回火焰山吧
Ok I'd better go back to the Flam Mountain
早知道要充军的话
I won't do this case
我们就不做这件案子啦
if I know this before
谁知道偷葡萄会那么大罪要充军呢
I don't know stealing grapes will make me suffer such punishment
早知道这样就不要做贼了嘛
If I know that, I won't be a robber
早知道就别做贼
Yes, sure
像我这样当兵
Like me, being a soldier
你们没有机会了
you have no chance yet
除非神仙来救你们
unless immortal comes to save you
早知道不当兵了
I won't be a soldier
真有神仙来救了
Immortal has come
神仙啊
Immortal!
晶晶
Jing Jing
菩提大哥
Granpa Buddha
他蒸呀蒸的是不是想蒸馒头
He steams byns
别多事啦
None of your business!
晶晶
Jing Jing!
嗯 你别再吃我豆腐啊
Don't flirt me!
人家喜欢你才吃你豆腐嘛
I flirt you because I love you
听着 你要做我的女人
Listen, if you want to be my wife
以后就别像你哥那样 为非作歹
don't do bad anymore in the future
哦 知道了
Sure!
走吧
Let's go
喝茶
Drink tea
麻烦你了
Thank you!
不要客气
You're welcome
唉 为什么带我回这个洞来
Why bring me back to this cave?
不是我带你来的
I didn't bring you back
是你昏倒迷迷糊糊带我们来的
It's you who brought us back
我一定是太想念晶晶了
It may be because I miss Jing Jing very much
是啊 你昏倒的时候
Yes! When you fainted
叫晶晶这个名字叫了九十八次
you spoke out the name Jing Jing 98 times!
晶晶是我娘子
Jing Jing is my wife
还有一个名字叫紫霞的
and a name Zixia
你叫了七百八十四次
You repeated 784 times
七百八十四次
784 times
这紫霞一定欠你很多钱
She must have owed you lots of money
我要拜盘丝大仙为师
I want Spider Web Cave Immortal to be my master
她分明把水帘洞改为盘丝洞
She's changed Waterfall Cave into Spider Web Cave
你们竟敢骗我说没这个人
You tell me there's no such person!
不知道啊
We don't know
臭猴子 原来你还在这儿
Son of a bitch, you're still here!
你为什么要这样对我
Why did you do that to me?
晶晶
Jing Jing
晶晶 再看到你太好了
Jing Jing, it's nice to see you
什么
What?
你瘦了
You've got thinner
我不是孙悟空啊
I'm not the Monkey King
但是我不知道怎么告诉你
But I don't how to tell you
因为你一定不会相信我
because you won't believe in it
我相信
I will
因为那个臭猴子不会对我这么温柔
Because that damn monkey won't be so gentle to me
你到底是谁
Who are you?
我就是你五百年后的老公
I'll be your husband 500 years later
五百年后
500 years later
你因为我而放弃现在这段感情
you will give up this affair because of me
我千辛万苦回这里来跟做所有事情
What I did is totally
完全都是为了你
just for you
晶晶 我想念你
Jing Jing, I miss you
我真的很想念你
I miss you much and much
我太想念你了
I miss you much and much and much
你相不相信
Don't you tryst me?
不相信
No!
这也不能怪你
I can't blame you
我看看该怎么
Let me see what's going on
不过我觉得我认识你
But I think I know you
绝对认识
Absolutely
而且很熟
Very and absolutely
非常的熟
Very and absolutely and extremely!
五百年之后 我们怎么认识的
How will we meet 500 years later?
在一个月黑风高阴森恐怖的晚上
At a pitch-dark night
我是至尊宝 你是白晶晶
I'm Joker, you're Pak Jing Jing
奇妙的爱情
Fantastic love
就从桥头上的这一点火开始的
starts from a fire at the bridge
我才一转身你就突如奇来向我一指
When I turn back you point at me with your finger
我整只手就着火了
then my hand gets burning
你还要冲过来向我打
you rush to me and hit me!
拼命的打
Hit and hit and hit!
不是 不是这样打
No...
是这样 这样
Look at me...
对啦 就是这样打的 你看到了吗
yes, can you see it!
以后的发展我可以用一句
there are many
峰回路转来形容
twists and turns
因为突然之间杀出一个牛魔王
Suddenly, the King Bull comes to us
当时你手拿一条龙骨大战牛魔王之后
I fight with him with a bone
还把我抓回盘丝洞里去
He grabbed me to the Spider Web Cave
所谓光阴似箭 真的一点也不错
It's right that time flies
因为才一转眼就说到重点了
The following is the main content
在断崖顶上 就是感情爆发的时候
On the cliff, we reach the climax
当时我不顾一切的摸你
At that time, I touch you
你也不顾一切的摸我
You touch me too
还立下永不分离的誓言
We make promise that we won't separate
可惜快乐永远都是短暂的
But happiness is always a flash of time
换来的只是无穷无尽的痛苦和长叹
We only have endless pain!
为什么你会死呢
Why will you die?
我当时只有利用月光宝盒使时光倒流
So I use the Box to travel back
查出真相
to the past
终于被我发现原来你是自杀的
I discover that you kill yourself
在最后关头
At the last moment
我终于能够把你救活
I save your life!
可是最后一次时光倒流
Byt at the last time of time travel
月光宝盒发生故障
the Box doesn't work properly
我“覷”的一声就回到五百年前
I go back to 500 years ago
就这样
That is the story
你 现在想怎么样
What are you gonna do now?
看到你 我不用再回去了
I've foynd you, I needn't go back now
我们成亲
Let's get married!
我 刚刚睡醒
I... I just wake up
经过外面无所事事
I have nothing to do
我就顺便进来拜师学艺的
So I come here. I wanna be a disciple
你突然跟我提到成亲这件事
You request marriage suddenly
我 牙齿还没有刷呢
I...haven't brushed my teeth!
我知道你心里面一定有怀疑
I know you're suspecting...
如果我可以把心掏出来给你看
If I can give you my heart
你就会知道我根本没有骗你
you'll know I'm not cheating you
很简单
it's very simple!
你怎么那么像
You look like a thing
椰子是嘛
Coconut?
以前有个女孩子也这么说过
A girl said that to me
那么椰子啊椰子
Oh, coconut
他刚刚说的话是不是真的
are his words all true?
别想了 照旧
No need to think!
你搜下面
You search the bottom!
谢谢你了 椰子
Coconut, thank you very much
那么请问你 他最喜欢的人是不是我啊
Please tell you, am I his best love?
哼 你回来这么久
You've come back for a long time
一天到晚跟我要月光宝盒
You just wanna get the Pandora's Box
什么意思啊
What do you mean?
我问你哪天跟我成亲
I'm asking you when we will get marry
你却一直推三推四
But you keep saying no
你到底嫁不嫁给我
Will you marry me?
I do
I do!
你妹妹是不是疯了
Is your sister crazy?
一个晚上讲鬼话
She keeps speaking nonsense all day long
她不是疯了 她是神经病
She's not crazy She's something wrong with the brain
神经病也行 只要她答应
If she promises...
七天后成亲
she has promised to marry him 7 days later
你真的决定嫁给他了
you have made up your mind?
我骗他的
I cheated him
我在等我的男人回来接我
I'm waiting for my man to pick me up!
你居然会相信那个小滑头会回来接你
You think that bastard will come to pick you up?
要是真的话 我可得恭喜你啦
Congratulations!
不过就算他回来
But even if he comes back
他有什么本事
he can't get you back
把你从牛魔王手上抢回去呀
from the King Bull
上天既然安排他能拔出我的紫青宝剑
It is fate that he can pull out my Magic Sword
他一定是一个不平凡的人
He must be an inordinary man
错不了
I'm sure
我知道有一天
I know he'll come back one day
他会在一个万众瞩目的情况下出现
appear in public
身披金甲圣衣
wearing golden armour
脚踏七色云彩来娶我
and stepping on colorful cloud come to marry me
还说不是神经病
You are crazy!
这不是神经病 是理想
I'm not crazy! This is jyst my hope
承认吧 小疯子
Promise me! Little psycho
不承认
No!
兄弟 世事难料
Bro, things are always unpredictable
没想到你这么快跟白姑娘成亲
I can't think you'll get marry with Miss Pak so soon
是呀 我自己也没想到
Yes, me too
我们都为你高兴
We're happy for you!
谢谢你
Thank you!
昨晚你做梦
You made dreams last night
又叫了紫霞姑娘的名字七百八十五次
You repeated the name Zixia 785 times
比上次多了一次
One time more than last night
过了六天了 明天晚上你就出嫁了
6 days have passed You'll get marry tomorrow
哼 他会来 才怪
He will come? I don't think so
昨天晚上我托一只蜘蛛跟你说
Yesterday, I told a spider to tell you
叫它告诉你 我很想念你
Told you I missed you much
你知不知道
Do you know?
你又知不知道
You don't know again
我一直在骗你
I am cheating you
骗就骗吧
That's fine!
就像飞蛾一样
Just like a moth
明知道会受伤还是会扑到火上
it flies to fire even it knows it'll get hurt
飞蛾就那么傻
Moth is so silly!
出来吧葡萄
Come out, grapes
我不是想监视你
I don't want to watch you
我只不过想研究一下
I just want to study
人与人之间的一些微妙的感情
the interesting relationship among humans
你只是强盗啊 大哥
Bro, you're a robber
别学人家做学问
Don't pretend to be a scholar
强盗也有学问
Even a robber has its own knowledge
你省省吧 睡啦
Stop it, go to sleep
紫霞在你心目中是不是一个惊叹号
In your mind is Zixia an exclamation mark?
还是一个句号
Or she's a full stop?
你脑袋里是不是充满了问号呢
Is your mind full of question marks?
紫霞只不过是个我认识的人
Zixia is just a girl who I know
我以前说过一个谎话骗她
I lied to her in the past
现在只不过心里面有一点内疚而已
I'm just feeling a little bit regretful
我越来越讨厌她
I hate him
我明天就要结婚了 你想怎么样呀
I'll get marry today. What do you want?
有一天当你发觉
When you discover that
你爱上一个你讨厌的人
you've fallen in love with a man you hate
这段感情才是最要命的
this affair is really hurting you
可是我怎么会爱上一个我讨厌的人呢
But how can I fall in love with a person I hate?
请你给我个理由好不好 拜托
Please give me a reason. Please!
爱一个人需要理由吗
We don't need any reason to love a person
不需要吗
Don't we?
需要吗
Do we?
不需要吗
Don't we?
需要吗
Do we?
不需要吗
Don't we?
哎 我跟你研究研究嘛
Let me stydy it for you
干嘛这么认真呢 需要吗
Why are you so serious? Need we?
谁
Who?
时辰到
Time's up
你有多少兄弟姐妹
How many brothers and sisters do you have?
你父母尚在吗
Are you parents alive?
你说句话啊
Speak up!
我只是想在临死之前
I just wanna make a new friend
多交一个朋友而已呀
when I'm going to die
糟了 怎么上去救师父
How to save Master?
所以说做妖就像做人一样
Being a devil is the same as being a human
要有仁慈的心
We should be kind
有了仁慈的心
If we are kind
就不再是妖 是人妖
we are not a devil, we are a hybrid
他明白了
He understand?
你明白了没有
do you understand?
没有人会来接你的 你省省吧 笨蛋
No one will come to pick you up
信
Your letter
谢了
Thank you
你的良心告诉我
Your conscience told me that
你最爱的不是我
I'm not your best love
而是另外一个女人
Your best love is another woman
当我见到她在你良心里面留下的东西之后
When I saw the thing left by her in your heart
我觉得 你经过这五百年
I know that you came back not for me
回来要找的不是我 而是她
but for her
你我都要相信 这是天意
This is God's order
也是传说中的缘份
It is also called fate
晶晶走了
Jing Jing's gone
我知道
I know
信我看过了
I've read the letter
菩提大哥
Granpa Buddha
他怎么啦
What's going on with her?
你们看过这封信了吗
Have you read this letter?
没有呀
No
你们看哪
You read it
好
Good
想走
Wanna go?
我知道我师妹白晶晶来过这里
I know my sister Pak Jing Jing has been here
她在哪里
Where is she now?
说
Speak up!
有那么大仇吗
Does she owe you this mych?
这么多年了你还不肯放过你师妹
You don't let your sister go
新郎官 你好像跟她很熟啊 干脆你告诉我啰
Just tell me
我不知道她在哪里
I don't know
不知道
听说你心肠不错啊
it is heard that you're kind
那些是你朋友
They are your friends?
不要啊
No!
你知道
Do you know?
如果你一定要杀人的话 就杀我吧
Kill me if you must kill someone
他们不认识你师妹的
They don't know your sister
他们全是无辜的
All of them are innocent
我同意
I agree!
我非常佩服不怕死的人
I admire bold people very much
既然这样
If you're one of them
那我成全你
I can fulfill your desire!
等一等
Wait!
我还真以为你不怕死呢
I really think that you aren't scared of death!
反正我要死了你就帮个忙
I'm gonna die. Please do me a favor
我听说过如果刀子出得快部位准
I've heard that if you cut fast and accurately
把人破开之后 人不会马上死掉
the man got hurt won't die at once when he's cut open
眼睛还看得见
He can still see
你就帮个忙 出手快一点
Help me, do it as fast as you can
把我的心挖出来
Tear out my heart
让我自己看行不行
Let you see it clearly
你说什么
What are you talking about?
我有个朋友说
A friend of mind
留了东西在我的心里面
Left something in my heart
我想看看到底是什么
I want to know what's that
莫名其妙
It's strange
人和妖精都是妈生的
Humans and devils are born by their mothers
不同的人是人他妈的
Different person acts as a different mom
妖呢 是妖他妈的
A devil's mom is a devil's mom
我受不了啦
I can take this
你妈贵姓啊
What's your name of your mom?
交拜天地
Kowtow to Heaven and Earth
美人 我们拜堂吧
Let's marry
等一等
Wait!
看
Look!
现在是妹妹要救姐姐
Now, she is the younger sister and she'll save her elder sister
等一会儿呢 那个姐姐一定会救妹妹的
The elder sister will save the younger sister
你又想干什么
What do you want?
我们今天都成亲了 你先放了我姐姐
We're married today. Let my sister go
我一定会遵守诺言
I won't break my promise
我不想再斗了
I don't want to fight anymore
你走吧
You go!
我这辈子就你这么一个姐姐
I just have one sister in my life
姐姐
Sister
牛魔王
King Bull!
我不会让我妹妹嫁给你的
I won't let my sister marry you
姐姐
Sister
你说什么
What are you talking about?
我这辈子也就你这么一个妹妹
I just have one sister in my whole life
你来吧
Come on!
看 我说对了吧
I'm right
居然比我还快
Faster than me
你真行
you're so great
是时候了
It's time
移形换影大法
Changing image
香香
Xiang Xiang?
我不是你妹妹
I'm not your sister
香香 你干什么
Xiang Xiang, what are you doing?
哥哥
Brother
哥哥 我的移魂大法
Brother, my Changing Image Magic...
香香
Xiang Xiang
把我移到狗的身上
Turn me into a dog
你是谁呀
Who are you?
我是青霞
I'm Qingxia!
姐姐
Sister...
我杀了你们
I will kill you
先救师父
Go to save Master!
不准打我姐姐
Don't hit my sister!
快来救我
Come to save us
把那个女的给我钉死
Kill that girl!
不可以
No!
-那是你妹妹 -走开
-It's you... -Go away!
谁拦着我 我就杀了谁
I'll kill the one who block my way
观音大世
Goddess
我开始明白你说的话了
I'm about to understand your words
以前我看事物 是用肉眼去看
I use my eyes to see
但是在我死去的那一刹那
When I'm dying
我开始用心眼去看这个世界
I use my heart to see this world
所有的事物
and all things
真的可以看得前所未有的那么清楚
I see it clearly
原来那个女孩子
That girl...
在我的心里面留下了一滴眼泪
Left a drop of tear in my heart
我完全可以感受到
I felt
她当时是多么的伤心
her sorrow
尘世间的事
Have you given up
你不再留恋了吗
all things in human world?
没关系了
Yes
生亦何哀
Life and death
死亦何苦
is minor
说得好 说得好
Great, great
恭喜 恭喜
Congratulations
怎么样 老兄
Bro, what's up?
来 坐坐坐
Come on, have a sit
你坐
Have a sit
最倒霉的是连累我的三位新朋友
It's unlucky that 3 friends of mine were get involved
-跟他们完全没有关系嘛 -唉 算了吧 别提了别提了
-It's none of their business! -Oh, forget it. Don't mention it.
不过我真的不明白
But I don't understand
恨一个人可以十年 五十年
Why can human hatred lasts 1 0 years 50 years
甚至五百年这样恨下去
and even 500 years?
为什么仇恨可以大到这种地步呢
What hatred is it?
所以唐三藏去取西经
So the Longevity Monk went to the west
他就是想指望这本经书
and got scriptures
去化解人世间的仇恨
which clean our heart
明白
Understand
我要留下来
I wanna stay. There are
因为还有事情等着我去做
many things waiting for me to do
你们自己跑快一点去投胎吧
You go to have your next lives as soon as possible!
好
Good!
这辈子我害你们被人砍了一刀
You're slashed because of me
希望下辈子有机会可以还
I hope I can pay you back in my next life
要还就还三刀
Pay back more
怎么说都行 亲爱的葡萄
I can do what I can do, grapes
好 我们走啦
We're leaving
再见 不送了
Goodbye
我要再提醒你一次
I wanna warn you again
金箍戴上之后
After wearing the Gold Ring
你再也不是个凡人
you're no longer a normal human
人世间的情欲不能再沾半点
You can't touch human desires anymore
如果动心
If you do so
这个金箍儿就会在你头上越收越紧
the Gold Ring will get smaller and smaller
苦不堪言
It's very uncomfortable
听到
Ok!
在戴上这个金箍之前
Before wearing this Ring
你还有什么话想说
what do you wanna say?
曾经有一份真诚的爱情摆在我的面前
I had my best love
但是我没有珍惜
But I don't treasure her
等到了失去的时候才后悔莫及
When I lost her, I felt regretful
尘世间最痛苦的事莫过于此
It is the most painful thing in this world
如果上天可以给我一个机会
If God can give me
再来一次的话
another chance
我会跟那个女孩说我爱她
I will say "I love you" to her!
如果非要把这份爱加上一个期限
If there is a time limit
我希望是 一万年
I hope...it is 10 thousand years
再叩首
Kowtow
三叩首
拜过祖师爷 喝过和亲酒
Kowtow to the forefather drink wedding wine
你就是我牛家的人了
Now you're a member of the Bull Family
云彩
Colorful clouds...
好大的棉花糖啊
Look like marshmallow
难道真的是他
Really?
小心哪
Be careful!
打雷啰
Thundering
下雨收衣服啊
It's raining, get the clothes
勾引我老婆的臭猴子
Damn monkey, you flirt with my life
熟归熟
Although we are friends
你这样乱讲话 我一样会告你毁谤
I'll indict you slander if you repeat again
给我杀了他
Kill him
对不起
Sorry!
这个喷嚏一定让大家很失望
This sneeZe may make you disappointed
至尊宝
Joker
这一次大家满足了吧
Are you satisfied this time?
师父
Master
哦 原来是悟空
It's the Monkey King
我还以为是片雨云
I just thought it's a piece of cloud
师父 弟子昔日罪孽深重
Master, I committed many offences in the past
幸得观音大世指点迷津
It's lucky that Goddess show a right road to me
现在已一心归于我佛
Now I'm gonna worship Buddha whole-heartedly
绝不会再留恋人世间半点情欲
I won't feel reluctant to give up human desires
护送师父去取西经这个重任
Master
弟子愿一肩承担
I will take the responsibility
善哉善哉
Great
你终于重返正途了
You're now on the right road
至尊宝
Joker
至尊宝 你终于来了
Joker, you're here eventually
姑娘
Miss!
我 的确认识一个朋友叫至尊宝
I... know a friend called Joker
他还有些话托一个叫紫霞仙子的人说
He ask me to tell Zixia Immortal something
是不是你啊
Is it you?
至尊宝
Joker
Stop
Stop!
我问是不是你
I'm asking you, is it you?
是不是
Is it you?
说呀
Speak up
对了
Yes
他说 他已经回到从前的地方
He said he had went back to the starting point
还希望仙子你能够
And he hoped that
早日找到一位如意郎君哪
she would find her best love as soon as possible
你别跟我开玩笑 至尊宝
Don't kid me, Joker
我再说一次
Let me tell you again
我的名字叫做 齐天大 圣
I'm the Monkey...King
不要再叫错了
Don't make any mistake
我今天要你的命
I'm gonna kill you today
变
Change!
打死你这只臭猴子
Beat you to death, damn monkey
看叉
Look oyt my fork
烤鸡翅膀 我最爱吃
I like barbecued chicken wing!
拿我叉子烤鸡翅膀
Use my fork to make barbecued chicken wing?
对了 我差点忘记了
I nearly forget it
我是吃斋的
I'm a vegetarian
还给我
Give me back!
觉得好不好玩哪 说来听听 说
Is it funny! Tell me!
说呀
Tell me...
为什么老是 不说话呢
Why are you so quiet?
快救我
Help me
对不起
Sorry
在你手下面前 我不应该让你这么丢脸
I don't want you lose face in front of your bros
我来帮你
Let me help you
还给你
Give back to you
好 看我的厉害
Great! Look out
无敌牛虱
Super bugs
我好怕呀 好多牛虱
I'm scared, so many bugs
幸亏我的猴崽子也不少
It's lucky that I have many little monkeys
把猴子通通杀了
Kill all the monkeys
让他杀
Let him kill
齐天大圣孙悟空是吗
Are you the Monkey King?
你不要去西天取西经吗
Will you go to the west to get scriptures?
带我一起去好不好
bring me with you
对啊
Yes!
有个女人一起去
She can act as a whore
寂寞的时候还有人可以当个慰安妇
if she goes with me
想起来真是
That's great...
我不行啦 我真的不行啦
I can't take this anymore
过来 搂着我
Come here, hold me tight!
你受不了我了
You can't take me anymore
受得了
I can
我受不了你呀
I can't take you anymore
你长得这么丑 帮个忙大家都是神仙
You're so ugly, we're immortals
不要再性骚扰我了 行不行
please no more sexual harassment
你为什么要这样对我
Why did you do that to me?
你生气啦
Are you angry?
我会生气的
I would get angry!
那就哭出来吧
Cry if you want
我送你们这些畜牲上西天
I'll kill you all bastards
芭蕉扇
Magic Fan
救我啊
Help me
真是麻烦
So troublesome!
师父
Master!
悟空 救我啊
Monkey King, help me!
我不相信你这样对我
I can't believe that you do that to me
你们两个保护师父
You two protect Master
知道了
I know
紫霞 不要
Zixia, no
你干什么
What are you doing?
你肯过来了吗
Will you come?
为什么那么关心我 让我死好了
Why are you so concerned about me? Let me die
我不是关心你
I'm not concerned about you
只不过蝼蚁尚且偷生
We'll treasure our lives
神仙干成你这个样子 干脆不要干算了
You are no immortals
孙悟空 你斗不过我的
Monkey King, you can't defeat me
好大条沟啊
What a wide ditch
接住 快接住
It's coming!
开什么玩笑
Stop kidding
我把整座城扇到太阳那边去
Put the whole city to the side of the sun
我看你救得了谁
Whom can you save now?
别妨碍我做正经事 要死就死远点
Don't bother me, you go to hell
等等
Wait!
还骗我
Lie to me again?
臭猴子把城顶住
Damn monkey how dare you stop my attack!
我扇
Go!
我把你顶回去
Go back!
糟了 太热 着火了
Shit, burning
混球
Stupid!
你又想怎么样啊 贱人
Bitch! What do you want?
混蛋
Stupid!
你才混蛋
you're stupid!
你不是人
You're not human
你才不是人
你不要再发疯了
Don't get mad
我刚才跟你说的话 你明不明白
Do you understand what I've told you?
你又明不明白 我已经不再是神仙了
Do you know I'm not an immortal now?
我只明白一件事
I only understand one thing
爱一个人是那么痛苦
Love means pain
不要跟我说这种废话
Don't bullshit with me
我说过你认错人啦
You've mistaken me!
那么这串金铃是在哪里买的
Where did you buy these gold rings?
小心
Be careful!
紫霞
Zixia
小心 师父
Master, look out!
紫霞
Zixia
我的意中人是个盖世英雄
My lover is a hero
有一天他会踩着七色云彩来娶我
One day he'll come with a cloud come to me and marry me
我猜中了前头
I've guessed the start
可是我猜不着这结局
But I haven't guessed the ending
师父
Master...
我要你的命
I want your life!
好热啊 快变烤猪了
It's very hot! you'll be a roast pig
这里快要爆炸了
It'll explode
一定要靠月光宝盒才能离开这里
We have to get the help of Pandora's Box
走
Go
快撞太阳了 快走
The sun is coming, hurry up
带师父走先
Bring Master go
快走
Hurry up!
青霞
Qingxia
我妹妹已经不在了
My sister is not here
我看我应该回如来佛祖那儿做灯芯
I think I should go back to be Buddha's lampwick again
你保重
Goodbye
大师兄 这么早就起来啦
Big Brother, you get up so early!
发生什么事啊
What's happened?
大师兄 你都忘记啦
Big Brother, you've forgot it
昨天晚上碰上一场大风沙
I met a storm last night
你把我们带到这里来的啦
You brought me here!
走
Go!
上哪儿去啊 师父
Master, where are we going now?
天竺
India
师父 怎么这么说话
Why does Master speak in this way?
师父说话一向简单明了 走吧
Master is a clear cut guy. Let's go
师父 别走那么快嘛
Master, walk slowly please
师兄 小心啊
Bro, be careful!
谢谢
Thanks!
相传五百年前这里就是水帘洞
It is said that this was the Waterfall Cave 500 years ago
齐天大圣住的地方
It's the living place of the Monkey King
自从他打死牛魔王
Since he's killed the King Bull
救回唐僧之后
and saved the Longevity Monk
这个世界再也没有妖怪了
there are no devils in the world
从此以后呢 很多人来这儿混水摸鱼
After that, many people came here fooling around
那个家伙
That guy put on a pig head
装个猪头居然说自己是猪八戒
and say that he's Piggy
哇 大哥啊
Bro
你化这个装就说自己是孙悟空哪
There is only make-upon your face
给点专业精神 好不好
Please be more professional
你看 那些毛通通都开叉了
Look at your hair
头上像戴了两块年糕似的
There are two cakes on your head
出来混饭吃得花点本钱嘛
You should pay more money to make yourself up
看什么看
What's up?
你的装是恶心嘛
Your image is really disgusting
生我气我也这么说
Don't angry at me I'm always an honest guy
我不会生气的
I won't get angry
再给我三刀吧
Cut me if you like
你以为我不敢啊 你这个混蛋
You son of bitch! Do you think I daren't do so?
多谢
Thanks
他为什么要我给他三刀呢
This is really sage
大师兄
Big Bro
师兄啊 准备出发了
Bro, let's go
菩提洞
Buddha Cave
好的 谢谢
Fine, thanks
谢谢
Thanks...
大师兄啊 你在看什么
Big Bro, what are you looking at?
八戒 卖豆腐那两个
Both girls who know Piggy
那两个
Who?
豆腐西施嘛
Beancurd Beauty
听这里的人说
It is heard that
她们辛辛苦苦卖豆腐
they sell beancurds
赚到钱
They have earned much money
是给她们相公上京考状元的
for their husbands to attend the civil service exam
状元到
The Highest Graduate
哎呀 媚娘啊媚娘
Mei!
真是恭喜你们啦 恭喜你们
Congratulations!
你们相公高中状元了
You husband has become the Highest Graduates of the exam
还不赶快去迎接他
Go to welcome him
哦 娘子
Honey
-相公 -娘子
-Honey -Honey
走开 三八 你看什么
Go away, no one of your business
娘子啊
Honey, Ah
辛苦娘子磨豆腐
You work so hard in making beancurds
辛苦娘子磨豆腐啊
You work so hard in making beancurd
相公
Honey
磨豆腐有什么了不起啊 我也会呀
I know how to make beancurds, too
走
Go!
走啰
吹个球
Blow the ball
吹个大气球
I blow the ball up
吹大了气球 玩球球
Blow the ball up and up
来这边看热闹
Come here!
有热闹可以看哪
It's crowded!
悟空
Monkey King
师父
Master
看看
Have a look
好
Ok!
这两个人啊 站在上面已经三天三夜了
They've stood there for 3 days
都没下来
They didn't
你们瞧 这个妖怪呀
Look, devil
看来我不应该来
I think I shouldn't come
现在才知道太晚了
It's too late
留下点回忆行不行
Leave some memories, Ok?
我不要回忆
I don't need memory
要的话 留下你的人
I want you
这样子只得到我的肉体
You can just get my body
并不能得到我的灵魂
instead of my spirit
我已经有爱人了
I've got a lover already
我们不会有结果
We won't have good result
你让我走吧
Let go of me
好 我让你走
I'll let you go
不过临走前你要亲我一下
But you have to kiss me before you've left
亲一下
Have a kiss...
亲啊
Kiss...
我再怎么说也是个夕阳武士
I'm just a powerless warrior
你叫我亲我就亲
If kiss you
那我的形象不是全毁了
my image will be ruined
你说谎
You're lying
你不敢亲我
You daren't kiss me
因为你还喜欢我
Because you still love me
我告诉你
I'm telling you
如果这次你拒绝我的话
If you reject me
你会后悔一辈子的
you'll regret for you whole life
后悔我也不会亲
I won't kiss you even if I regret
只能怪相逢恨晚 造物弄人啊
It's fate
我这辈子都不会走
I will stay here for my whole life
我爱你
I love you
干什么
What's up?
那个人样子好怪啊
That guy looks strange
我也看到了
I know
♪ 无言独坐 放眼尘世外（愿来日再续） ♪
他好像条狗啊
He looks like a dog!
♪ 鲜花虽会凋谢（只愿） 但会再开（为你） ♪
♪ 一生所爱 隐约（守候）在白云外（期待） ♪
♪ 苦海翻起爱恨 在世间难逃避命运 ♪
♪ 相亲竟不可接近 或我应该相信是缘份 ♪